University of Connecticut
© 2008 University of Connecticut
University of Connecticut, Women's Studies Program Records.
undated, 1979-2007.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
University of Connecticut. Women's Studies Program.
.75 linear feet.
MSS20080003
The Women's Studies Program at the University of Connecticut began in 1974 and was the first formal program of its kind in the state. The collection consists of Connecticut Humanities Council grant files, administrative records, announcement, fliers and publications.
History
The Women's Studies Program at the University of Connecticut began in 1974 and was the first formal program of its kind in the state.
The Women's Studies Program is a flexible interdisciplinary academic program devoted to the critical analysis of gender and the pursuit of knowledge about women. Combining methods and insights of traditional academic disciplines with the special insights of Women's Studies scholarship, our courses yield fresh perspectives, which illuminate the origins of and changes in diverse cultural and social arrangements. Additional information on the program is available on the program website.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains files pertaining to a 1982 Connecticut Humanities Council grant, administrative files, publications, announcements and fliers.
Researchers are reminded to request the Subject file for "Women's Studies" for materials dated after 2007.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically in one series.
Series I: Files ( undated, 1979-2007 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)
Subjects:
Document Types:
Publications.; Administrative Records.; Press releases.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Photocopies.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The materials in the collection have been pulled from transfers of faculty files, administrative transfers and internal collection of ephemeral materials.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Files, undated, 1979-2007
  - Connecticut Humanities Council Grant on Women, 1982
    - Administrative files (Box 1:, Folder 1-3)
    - Financial records (Box 1:, Folder 4-5)
  - Connecticut Humanities Council pamphlet, 1984 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut Humanities Council program, 1983 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Connecticut Women: A Radio Series, 1981 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Files, circa 1980-1981 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Fliers and announcements, 1979-2007 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Logo (old), ore 1995 (Box 2:, Folder 11)
  - Personal Lives and Professional Careers: The Uneasy Balance, Lois Banner (copy of foreward), undated (Box 2:, Folder 12)
  - Program brochure, 198? (Box 2:, Folder 13)
  - Women's Semester Internship Handbook, 1986, 1988 (Box 2:, Folder 14)